Example of an academic CV

Jo Ellis

Telephone: 01324 456789 Mobile: 07717 121822 Email: jo.ellis245@coolmail.com

Home address: University address:

Flat 30 School of Environmental Science

The Meadows University of Ribbington

19 Floral Park Rough Lane

Salisbury SA12 1BH Ribbington RJ1 5BT

Current research

I am investigating the relationship between tree mould and industrial effluent in the Ribbington Canal Basin area, which is part of a larger study carried out by the School of Environmental Science on behalf of Ribbington Borough Council and the Environment Agency.

My principal investigator is Professor Mark Wood and I am responsible for the collection, testing and analysis of canal water samples.

This post-doctoral research draws directly upon my PhD investigation of the changes in ecosystems in the Canal Basin area in which I focused on changes in water quality following the development of new industrial processes adjacent to the canal. My thesis was awarded the 2011 ECONET prize for development of what has become known as the 'King Test' of water quality.

Use of a named supervisor can help locate your work within the discipline.

Show you

have given thought to what

might be developed.

Research ambition

My plans include development and refinement of the King Test and adapting its use for water treatment plants and other environmental purposes.

Education and qualifications

2008 – 2011 Full-time (ECONET) research PhD

studentship

School of Environmental Science,

University of Ribbington.

2005 – 2008 Full-time student BSc in Environmental Science

Modern College of Agriculture, (1st class).

Derbyshire.

London.

1998 – 2005 Full-time student A level in Biology (A*), Maths

Aspiring High School, (A) and Statistics (B).

spiring riight school, (A) and statistics (b).

10 GCSEs including Maths,

English and Science.

		_		
Ρı	ıh	licat	ion	c

King, J. (2012) 'Developing the King Test' in Wood, M., et al (2012) *Water Test Update 5,* Ribbington Occasional Papers.

Wood, M., Parson, F., and King, J., (2010) Water Quality: Why it Matters, Milton Keynes, OU Press.

Conference papers

King, J., and Maloney, P., (2009) 'Beginning Research' in *Association of Scientific Students Annual Conference*, at the University of Ribbington, 14 July

Teaching experience

Five hours per week undergraduate teaching in the 'Introducing Environmental Science' module (ES001).

Supervisory support of two undergraduate dissertation projects (two hours per term) in Year 3.

Include
other
student
contact
work,
such as
mentoring
schemes.

Work experience

2012 – presentPost-doctoral researcherContract due to end on 27 JulySchool of Environmental Science,2013.University of Ribbington.

2009 – 2010 Part-time stock controller Temporary employment.

Jolly Fine Foods, Salisbury SZ3 7TJ.

Memberships

Associate Member of the Institute for Water Speculators.

Additional skills

- Competent user of Microsoft packages including PowerPoint, Word and Excel.
- Proficient user of SPSS, Stata and Access.

Conferences attended

August 2010 Society of Water Engineers Conference, Metropolitan University of Amsterdam.

July 2009 Association of Scientific Students Annual Conference held at the University of Fife.

References

Professor Mark Wood, Course Leader, School of Environmental Science, Ribbington RJ1 5BT.

Email: m.wood@ribbington.ac.uk

Use both academic and non-academic referees.

Miss L Break, Store Manager, Jolly Fine Foods, Salisbury SZ3 7TJ.

Email: lbreak@finefoods.co.uk